Now that you've seen the use of color and visuals,
学完了颜色在可视化中的应用
let's look at a few additional encodings.
我们再来看一下其他的视觉编码
Sometimes you'll need additional encodings to distinguish data in a visual.
有时候 你需要额外的视觉编码来区分一个图形中的数据
For these cases, you might want to use different encoding such as shape or size.
在这种情况下 你可能想使用形状或者大小
In a scatter plot,
在散点图中
we might change the size or shape of the markers.
我们可以改变数据点的大小或形状
In this video, you will learn about some additional encodings.
在本视频中 你将学习一些额外的可视化编码形式
When you're making scatter plot,
制作散点图时
you're representing the data with dots,
你将用点来展示数据
or maybe some other symbol.
或者是其他一些符号
Here, we are comparing the average SAT scores for students at different universities.
这里 我们比较不同大学学生的 SAT 平均分
Each point is the information of a single university.
每个点代表一所大学的信息
Right now, the visual encoding of the data is oppositional,
现在 每个数据的视觉编码是跟位置相关的
only using the x and y axes.
仅使用 x 轴与 y 轴
If these are the only two columns we want to encode,
如果我们只想对这些内容编码
I can't imagine a visual that paints the relationship in a more clear way.
我不知道还有什么比这图表更清晰的表示方式
However, we could introduce
然而 我们可以引入
additional encodings to show additional features in our dataset.
额外的编码来展示我们数据集里额外的一些特征
Say whether the school is private or public.
例如 区分学校是私立的还是公立的
Now, imagine we also want to understand
如果我们也想了解
the student-faculty ratios associated with each school.
每所学校的师生比
We will need another encoding.
我们需要另一个编码
Even though we get a lot of information from the marker size,
虽然我们能从标志大小获得很多信息
it's not a very accurate representation.
但这也不是非常精准的展现
It can also be ambiguous as to how the size should be interpreted.
比如要如何诠释标志的尺寸
Should the viewer be comparing the diameter of the marker or the area?
读者应该比较标志的直径还是面积？
Data can also be encoded using different shapes,
数据也可以用不同的形状来编码
but we don't encode quantitative data with shapes as we
但对于数值型数据 我们一般不用形状来编码
probably run out of the number of shapes to encode our values.
因为可能没有足够多的形状来对所有数值进行呈现
You would instead need to change your data to a categorical ordinal variable,
你需要把数据转换成有序分类变量
and encoding quantitative data with color can be confusing.
使用颜色编码数值型数据也可能导致困扰
Look at this example.
看一下这个例子
The shapes are not as great as color for differentiating the schools,
形状不能像颜色那样有效地区分学校
and the colors here are hardly an indicator of all the different student-faculty ratios.
这里的颜色很难作为所有不同的师生比的指标
In general, color and shape are best used for categorical variables,
一般而言 颜色和形状最好用在分类变量上
while the size of the marker can assist in adding
标志的大小有助于
additional quantitative data as we demonstrated here.
添加额外的数值变量信息 正如我们之前说到的
I personally try to avoid these types of encodings if possible.
我个人是尽量避免使用额外视觉编码方式的
But sometimes these additional encodings are necessary.
但是 有时候这些额外编码又是有必要的
If you start to lose the message,
如果害怕不能展示所有信息
consider breaking your visual into more visuals that each conveys its own direct message.
可以考虑把一个图表分成多个图表 每个图表传递各自的直观信息